authsmtp.com 2019-04-12

# Privacy Policy

## 1\. Privacy Statement

1.1. GetOnline Ltd trading as 'AuthSMTP' (the "Vendor") operates h​ttps://www.authsmtp.com and h​ttps://www.authsmtp.co.uk (the "Websites"). 

1.2. This page informs you (the "Visitor") of the Vendor policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information that is received from Visitors of the Websites and via other communication channels such as email or physical mail, where no formal agreement exists between the Vendor and the Visitor.

1.3. The primary purpose of the Websites is to advertise the Service which is an authenticated SMTP relay server along with other ancillary websites and functions (the "Service").

1.4. The Vendor will use any Personal Information provided, to personalize the Websites and to contact the Visitor about the Service. If the Visitor chooses to, the Vendor may occasionally contact the Visitor about the Service, related activities or other services provided by the Vendor. The vendor will never share or sell the Visitor's Personal Information with third parties.

1.5. Should the Visitor enter into an agreement with the Vendor to use the Service, the agreement will be subject to the Terms of Service and the separate Service Privacy Policy.

## 2\. Eligibility to use these Websites

2.1 By using the Websites, the Visitor agrees to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

2.2 Under no circumstances should the Visitor provide the Vendor with any information that would be classed as Sensitive Personal Information as defined in article 9 of the GDPR regulations, this includes (but is not limited to) any of the following:

  * a. Race
  * b. Ethnic origin
  * c. Political views
  * d. Religious views
  * e. Trade union membership
  * f. Genetic data
  * g. Biometric data
  * h. Health data
  * i. Sexual orientation

2.3. The Service is primarily a business to business service, to be eligible to use the Websites and the Service the Visitor must be aged 18 or over.

## 3\. Information Collection, Use and Retention (Websites)

3.1. The h​ttps://www.authsmtp.com website is hosted on a private, dedicated web server in the United States.

3.1.1 Any data collected on that website is temporarily stored on that server before being transferred to the United Kingdom.

3.2. The h​ttps://www.authsmtp.co.uk website is hosted on a private, dedicated web server in the United Kingdom.

3.2.1 Any data collected on that website will remain in the United Kingdom.

3.3. While using the Websites, the Vendor may ask the Visitor to provide their country of residence via a browser function so that the Vendor can customise the Websites to the local or nearest applicable currency. This information is stored using a cookie on the users computer, it is not stored or retain by the Vendor.

3.4. If the Visitor chooses to contact the Vendor via the websites, the following information will be requested:

  * Full Name
  * Company Name
  * Website Name
  * Contact Email Address
  * Enquiry Information
  * Marketing Opt-In (defaults to opt-out)

3.5. Depending on the nature of the query, the Vendor may need to ask for further information which will be subject to the same policies as any of the information listed above. This information will be stored for a maximum of 3 years and 1 month and then will be deleted.

3.6. If the Visitor chooses to receive marketing emails, they have the option of opting out at any time via the email links provided.

3.7. The Vendor will never ask for, and the Visitor should never offer the following information:

  * a. Sensitive Personal Information
  * b. Account Passwords

## 4\. Information Collection, Use and Retention (Direct Email)

4.1. The primary email service for direct messages to authsmtp.com and authsmtp.co.uk is hosted on a private email server in the United Kingdom.

4.2. If the Visitor sends a direct email message, the Vendor will store the full message itself, any subsequent replies and the related log data for a maximum of 3 years and 1 month and then they will be deleted.

4.3. The Vendor will never ask for, and the Visitor should never offer the following information:

  * a. Sensitive Personal Information
  * b. Account Passwords

## 5\. Information Collection, Use and Retention (Other)

5.1. The primary channels of communication are via email and the Websites, communication via other channels such as telephone or the physical postal services are not offered.

5.2. Any unsolicated communication received via these other channels will have the same privacy policies applied as our primary communication channels wherever possible.

## 6\. Log Data

6.1. Like many website operators, the Vendor will automatically collect information from the Visitors browser whenever they visit the Websites (the "Log Data").

6.2. This Log Data may include information such as the computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser version, the pages of the Websites that were visited, the time and date of the visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.

6.3. In addition, the Vendor may use third party services such as Google Analytics that will anonymously collect, monitor and analyze Website activity - no Personal Information will be shared with these third parties.

6.4. Log data will be stored for a maximum of 6 years and 1 month.

## 7\. Data Transfers, Sharing and Disclosure

7.1. The Vendor will not share, sell or disclose the Visitor's Personal Information to any persons or companies outside of the Vendor organization.

7.2. Information and log data collected on the United States hosted website (https://www.authsmtp.com) will be transferred to the United Kingdom for the processing activities and data retention periods listed above.

7.3. Information and log data collected on the United Kingdom hosted website (https://www.authsmtp.co.uk) will remain in the United Kingdom for the processing activities and data retention periods listed above.

7.4. Other than the activity listed above, the Vendor will not transfer the Visitor's Personal Information outside of the United Kingdom for any purpose.

## 8\. Cookies

8.1. Cookies are files with small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to the browser from a website and stored on the computer's hard drive.

8.2. Like many sites, the Vendor use "cookies" to collect information. A Visitor can instruct their browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if the Visitor do not accept cookies, they may not be able to use some portions of the Website.

## 9\. Security

9.1. The security of Personal Information is of upmost importance but it should be noted that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While the Vendor strives to use commercially acceptable means to protect Personal Information, the Vendor cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## 10\. Consent

10.1. By using the Website, the Visitor agrees to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

10.2 If the Visitor provides additional Personal Information described in section 3 of this document, further consent will be sought before the information can be submitted.

10.3. To withdraw consent the Visitor should cease accessing the Websites and remove any related cookies.

10.4. For information on how to remove cookies please visit [https://cookiesandyou.com](https://cookiesandyou.com/).

## 11\. Data Access Request

11.1. To request a copy of any information that the Vendor holds in connection with a Visitor name and email address, please visit:

Data Subject Access Request

## 12\. Data Deletion Request

12.1. To request deletion of any information that the Vendor holds in connection with a Visitor name and email address, please visit:

Data Deletion Access Request

## 13\. Contact

13.1. For any questions about this policy, please contact the Vendor data protection team using the email address dpo@authsmtp.com.

## 14\. Changes to this policy

14.1. This policy is effective as of ​the 25th of May 2018 and will remain in effect except with respect to any changes in its provisions in the future, which will be in effect immediately after being posted on this page.

14.2. The Vendor reserves the right to update or change the policy at any time and the Visitor should check this policy periodically. The continued use of the Website after the Vendor posts any modifications to the policy on this page will constitute the Visitors acknowledgment of the modifications and consent to abide and be bound by the modified policy.

14.3. If the Vendor make any material changes to the policy, the Vendor will notify by placing a prominent notice on the Website.

## 15\. Current Version

15.1. The version reference for this website privacy policy is:

WPP-1.0.1
